<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>brain dump</title>
    <link>https://carlosolmos.dev/</link>
    <description>Recent content on brain dump</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 15:52:52 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://carlosolmos.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The MacroPad Jukebox</title>
      <link>https://carlosolmos.dev/posts/the-macropad-jukebox/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 15:52:52 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://carlosolmos.dev/posts/the-macropad-jukebox/</guid>
      <description>The jukebox 🔗Lately, I&amp;rsquo;ve been obsessed with the old way of listening to music. You know: from your own collection, in order, one album at a time. No randomness, no infinite playlists, no album of the day, no ads, and no algorithms. When I got my hands on an Adafruit MacroPad RP2040 I knew what I had to do: make my own ugly and overengineered music player. I present to you the &amp;ldquo;MacroPad Jukebox&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abandonware: evaluating the health of the libraries in your project</title>
      <link>https://carlosolmos.dev/posts/abandonware-evaluating-the-health-of-the-libraries-in-your-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2022 19:10:44 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://carlosolmos.dev/posts/abandonware-evaluating-the-health-of-the-libraries-in-your-project/</guid>
      <description>Open Source Dependencies 🔗I find it very interesting how comfortable we, software engineers, have become with the notion of including thousands, and thousands, of lines of code we know nothing about in our projects. I don&amp;rsquo;t think reusing open-source libraries is bad. Quite the opposite; I am convinced that software development based on open-source software (OSS) is what allows us to move ahead in the industry at a fast pace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shake It! - Remote sensor activation using the Arduino IoT Cloud</title>
      <link>https://carlosolmos.dev/posts/shake-it-remote-sensor-activation-using-the-arduino-iot-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 15:29:48 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://carlosolmos.dev/posts/shake-it-remote-sensor-activation-using-the-arduino-iot-cloud/</guid>
      <description>The challenge 🔗While working with the Everactive Development Kit that I keep at home, I often need to interact with the sensors physically —to test our motion sensor, for example. This of course forces me to have the kit close by, which is inconvenient. I would like to be able to activate the sensors remotely when I am working from the office or my favorite coffee shop.
On the other hand, I have been looking for an excuse to use the Arduino IoT Cloud service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Node-RED and the Everactive API - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://carlosolmos.dev/posts/node-red-and-the-everactive-api-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 19:01:59 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://carlosolmos.dev/posts/node-red-and-the-everactive-api-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Node-RED is a great tool for low-code IoT programming. Its drag &amp;amp; drop interface allows you to wire hardware and software to get data flowing in no time. It&amp;rsquo;s open source and there is plenty of documentation and helpful resources around. In this article -the first of two parts- we are going to create a very simple workflow to fetch data from the Everactive API, and a public data service, and then apply a very simple thresholding function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Load environment variables from a file in the terminal (zsh)</title>
      <link>https://carlosolmos.dev/posts/load-environment-variables-from-a-file-in-the-terminal-zsh/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 18:34:24 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://carlosolmos.dev/posts/load-environment-variables-from-a-file-in-the-terminal-zsh/</guid>
      <description>Load environment variables from a file* 🔗To load shell environment variables from a simple KV configuration file like:
click to zoom in Add this alias to your .zshrc file
alias loadEnv=&amp;#39;function _loadEnv() { set -o allexport; source $1; set +o allexport };_loadEnv&amp;#39; click to zoom in And you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to load environment variables really easy:
click to zoom in </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everactive Edge Webhooks, Fluentd, and S3</title>
      <link>https://carlosolmos.dev/posts/everactive-edge-webhooks-fluentd-and-s3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 20:22:46 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://carlosolmos.dev/posts/everactive-edge-webhooks-fluentd-and-s3/</guid>
      <description>From Everactive&amp;rsquo;s Webhook Subscriptions to Fluentd &amp;amp; S3 🔗 Disclaimer: this solution is totally overengineered. Only for learning purposes. You don&amp;rsquo;t want to use this in production, or do you?&amp;hellip;😜
 Everactive’s Managed Network ensures connectivity, uptime, and reliable &amp;amp; secure data transfer into our Platform. We understand that you need a steady stream of new data to transform into high-value insights to package as innovative, hyper-scale IoT applications to your end users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everactive Edge API and Pipedream</title>
      <link>https://carlosolmos.dev/posts/everactive-edge-api-and-pipedream/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2022 20:22:46 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://carlosolmos.dev/posts/everactive-edge-api-and-pipedream/</guid>
      <description>The Everactive Edge RESTful API gives you direct programmatic access to the data returned by Eversensors. The API provides endpoints to retrieve data based on time ranges, and shortcuts to get the last-available reading from a particular sensor. Typically, applications will poll these endpoints to get the most up-to-date information. In this article, we are going to use Pipedream.com as a mechanism to periodically poll the API for new data and log it in a spreadsheet on Google Docs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instrumenting applications with Prometheus</title>
      <link>https://carlosolmos.dev/posts/instrumenting-applications-with-prometheus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2022 22:10:52 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://carlosolmos.dev/posts/instrumenting-applications-with-prometheus/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;What is not defined cannot be measured. What is not measured, cannot be improved. What is not improved, is always degraded&amp;rdquo;. William Thomson Kelvin
 In this article, we will learn how to create custom metrics for a simple web application and use Prometheus to collect and report on them.
Site Reliability Engineering 🔗This post is part of a series about Site Reliability Engineering (SRE). In the series, we will talk about different concepts, tools, and techniques to keep a large-scale system healthy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MQTT with RabbitMQ</title>
      <link>https://carlosolmos.dev/posts/mqtt-with-rabbitmq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 22:21:32 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://carlosolmos.dev/posts/mqtt-with-rabbitmq/</guid>
      <description>MQTT is a widely used protocol in the IoT world. It is a lightweight pub/sub messaging system, with a small code footprint and minimal bandwidth requirements, which makes it ideal for connecting remote small devices. To implement the MQTT protocol you need a robust broker service to handle the connections and the messages transportation.
RabbitMQ is one of the most popular message brokers in the market. It is easy to deploy and solves all kinds of messaging requirements at small and large scales.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI Colonialism</title>
      <link>https://carlosolmos.dev/posts/ai-colonialism/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 21:39:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://carlosolmos.dev/posts/ai-colonialism/</guid>
      <description>From the MIT Technology Review:
Artificial Intelligence is creating a new colonial world order.
Big tech is following concerning patterns when deploying their services in developing countries. Just like the colonialists of the past, this companies are extracting value from vulnerable communities for their enrichment. This MIT Technology Review series of articles is a real eye-opener.
 &amp;ldquo;The AI industry does not seek to capture land as the conquistadors of the Caribbean and Latin America did, but the same desire for profit drives it to expand its reach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Today I Learned: How to make a blog with Hugo</title>
      <link>https://carlosolmos.dev/posts/today-i-learned-how-to-make-a-blog-with-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://carlosolmos.dev/posts/today-i-learned-how-to-make-a-blog-with-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Using Hugo to Create a Static Blog 🔗This site was initially created by following this guide:
Create your own free blog website using Hugo in less than 1 hour</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
