<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Brain dump</title>
    <link>https://carlosolmos.dev/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Brain dump</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 22:21:32 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://carlosolmos.dev/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>MQTT with RabbitMQ</title>
      <link>https://carlosolmos.dev/posts/mqtt-with-rabbitmq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 22:21:32 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://carlosolmos.dev/posts/mqtt-with-rabbitmq/</guid>
      <description>MQTT is a widely used protocol in the IoT world. It is a lightweight pub/sub messaging system, with a small code footprint and minimal bandwidth requirements, which makes it ideal for connecting remote small devices. To implement the MQTT protocol you need a robust broker service to handle the connections and the messages transportation.
RabbitMQ is one of the most popular message brokers in the market. It is easy to deploy and solves all kinds of messaging requirements at small and large scales.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI Colonialism</title>
      <link>https://carlosolmos.dev/posts/ai-colonialism/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 21:39:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://carlosolmos.dev/posts/ai-colonialism/</guid>
      <description>From the MIT Technology Review:
Artificial Intelligence is creating a new colonial world order.
Big tech is following concerning patterns when deploying their services in developing countries. Just like the colonialists of the past, this companies are extracting value from vulnerable communities for their enrichment. This MIT Technology Review series of articles is a real eye-opener.
 &amp;ldquo;The AI industry does not seek to capture land as the conquistadors of the Caribbean and Latin America did, but the same desire for profit drives it to expand its reach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Today I Learned: How to make a blog with Hugo</title>
      <link>https://carlosolmos.dev/posts/today-i-learned-how-to-make-a-blog-with-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://carlosolmos.dev/posts/today-i-learned-how-to-make-a-blog-with-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Using Hugo to Create a Static Blog 🔗This site was initially created by following this guide:
Create your own free blog website using Hugo in less than 1 hour</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
